digikey.in 2019-06-26

# Privacy Statement | DigiKey Electronics

Revision 2.0

## DATE OF LAST MODIFICATION

## May 25, 2018

We welcome you to the Digi-Key® Web Site. We provide this Privacy Statement to inform you on how we use and manage the information collected at Digi-Key. This Privacy Statement applies to any website or mobile application that includes, attaches, references, or links to this Privacy Statement ("Web Site"). The Digi-Key Web site may contain links to other websites. Digi-Key does not control or take responsibility for personal information collected on these sites nor is Digi-Key responsible for the accuracy or the content of these sites. This Privacy Statement is intended to cover the operations of Digi-Key Corporation doing business as Digi-Key Electronics and its subsidiary Digi-Key Electronics Germany GmbH, which together shall be referred to as "Digi-Key."

For those of you accessing this Web Site from the European Union, Digi-Key Electronics, a U.S. based company, headquartered at 701 Brooks Ave South, PO Box 677, Thief River Falls, Minnesota USA 56701-0677, is the responsible body and controller as defined by data protection laws:

### 1\. Types And Use Of Information We Collect From You

**Customer Information** \- During a Web Site visit, we may ask a customer for contact information (such as name, title, company name, email address, telephone number, fax number and addresses for shipping/billing, and credit card information, when applicable) as part of the purchase process, to become a registered user of the Web Site, when you request information from or submit a question to Digi-Key, and when you complete any web forms asking for such information.

_Purchases –_

Once you make a purchase, become a registered user, or request information from Digi-Key, your name, title, company name, shipping/mailing address, telephone number, email address, fax number, financial and credit card, and other information may be included in our customer file. We use commercially reasonable security to protect the data you provide as a part of making purchases from the Web Site as stated in the Security portion of this Privacy Statement.

_Registration –_

Registration may be required to access and use certain parts of the Web Site, such as for making a purchase. Registered users are able to change or delete the data they provide upon registration at any time if required by law, and we will provide you with information about the personal data we have saved about you at any time. We will correct and delete such data at your request as long as doing so does not conflict with any legally required retention obligations. To contact us to review, edit, or delete data collected about you, please use the contact information located at the end of this Privacy Statement.

_Comments Function –_

If you leave comments where allowed on the Web Site, such as in a blog or other portion of the Web Site that allows user generated content, various information about you and the comment may also be saved and associated with the comment, such as your user name, the time of the post, and information that is automatically collected as described in this Privacy Statement in addition to the comments themselves.

_Newsletter Signup –_

If you subscribe to our newsletter, the information you provide is used for this purpose in addition to the purposes stated in the Use of Information section of this Privacy Statement and you consent to its use for these purposes. We might also use e-mail to inform subscribers of information relevant for this service or for the subscription itself (for example, changes to the newsletter offering or technical issues). You can withdraw your consent of our use of your newsletter signup information for sending you newsletters by using the opt-out procedure stated in the newsletter.

_Contact Form –_

If you contact us by email or by using one of our contact forms, the information you provide will be saved and used to respond to your contact as well as for the purposes stated in the Use of Information section of this Privacy Statement and you consent to its use for these purposes.

**Use of Information** \- We use this information to fulfill your orders and otherwise provide the products and services you request, as well as support for those products and services. We may use customer information to send you information and advertising about Digi-Key and its products and services. For example, Digi-Key may use your mailing address to send Digi-Key marketing materials to keep you updated on our most current products and services and email addresses may be used to communicate information of interest to you about Digi-Key. This includes Order Shipment/Tracking Information, Obsolete Part Bulletins, Service Change Information or other Digi-Key promotional emails. You may elect to opt out of any or all of these emails by completing the "[Opt Out Form](https://www.digikey.in/classic/forms/dkc/www/servicesoptout.aspx?FormSite=IN&FormLang=en&site=IN&lang=en)." Emails may be sent to you by Digi-Key or an authorized agent working for Digi-Key. We also reserve the right, but not the obligation, to contact you regarding changes to this Privacy Statement and other matters relevant to the Web Site.

### 2\. Information Automatically Collected

When you visit the Web Site, we collect some information of a general nature automatically. By collecting this information we get a better understanding of your needs and preferences, what products and services we can develop to meet those needs and preferences, and how well Digi-Key’s Web Site is functioning. Some of the information we automatically collect is necessary for the proper functioning of the Web Site, such as cookies as explained below. We treat information collected by cookies and other technologies as non-personal information. However, to the extent that Internet Protocol (IP) addresses or similar identifiers are considered personal information by local law, we also treat these identifiers as personal information. Similarly, to the extent that non-personal information is combined with personal information, we treat the combined information as personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Statement.

**Links, Embedded Content, and Buttons** – Digi-Key may keep track of how you interact with links across our services, including our email notifications. We do this to help improve our services, provide information and advertising, and to be able to analyze aggregate click statistics such as how many times a particular link was clicked on. The Web Site may contain links to other websites, content embedded in the Web Site that comes from or relates to other websites and services, and buttons from other websites and services such as social media websites like YouTube, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Instagram, and Google+. In general, you can identify these social media buttons and the companies they represent by their logos. Buttons on the Web Site may be presented using tools and the toolbar provided by the third party AddThis. AddThis provides its own, separate privacy policy related to its tools and toolbar, which you may view here: <http://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy>. AddThis also provides an opt-out mechanism related to their services here: <http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out> and also here, in relation to their e-mail sharing: <http://www.addthis.com/privacy/email-opt-out>. Several of these third parties may use cookies or other tracking devices to collect and track information about you over time and across the Internet. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these other websites or their data collection practices. You should check the privacy policies of these other websites when providing personally identifiable information or to find out what other information they collect from users, whether while on their platform or website or in relation to links, buttons, or embedded media. At present, it is reasonable to assume that a direct connection to the services of the provider is established and that at least your IP address and device-related information are collected and used. The service providers might also attempt to save cookies on the computer used. Note: If you are logged into Facebook at the same time, Facebook may be able to identify you as a visitor to a specific page.

**Presently, and subject to change in our discretion and without notice, we have embedded the social media buttons of the following companies on our Website:**

**Facebook Inc.**

  * If you live in the US or Canada:
  * Facebook Inc.
  * 1601 Willow Road
  * Menlo Park, CA 94025
  * USA

  * If you live anywhere but in the US or Canada:
  * Facebook Ireland Ltd.
  * 4 Grand Canal Square
  * Grand Canal Harbour
  * Dublin 2 Ireland

Data Policy: <https://www.facebook.com/policy.php>

**Instagram**

  * Facebook, Inc.
  * ATTN: Privacy Operations
  * 1601 Willow Road
  * Menlo Park, CA 94025
  * USA

Data Policy: <https://help.instagram.com/519522125107875?helpref=page_content>

**Twitter Inc.**

  * For accounts based in the United States:
  * Twitter, Inc.
  * Attn: Privacy Policy Inquiry
  * 1355 Market Street, Suite 900
  * San Francisco, CA 94103
  * USA

  * For accounts outside the United States:
  * Twitter International Company
  * Attn: Privacy Policy Inquiry
  * One Cumberland Place, Fenian Street
  * Dublin 2, D02 AX07 IRELAND

Privacy Policy: <https://twitter.com/en/privacy>

  * **Google Plus/Google Inc./Youtube**
  * 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway
  * Mountain View, CA 94043
  * USA

Privacy Policy: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>

**LinkedIn Corporation**

  * For members in the United States:
  * LinkedIn Corporation
  * Attn: Legal Dept. (Privacy Policy and User Agreement)
  * 1000 W. Maude Avenue
  * Sunnyvale, CA 94085
  * USA

  * For members outside the United States:
  * LinkedIn Ireland Unlimited Company
  * Attn: Legal Dept. (Privacy Policy and User Agreement)
  * Wilton Plaza
  * Wilton Place, Dublin 2
  * Ireland

Privacy Policy: <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/preview/privacy-policy>

**Information From Your Computer** – Digi-Key may itself, or through our third party service providers, collect information about your computer, such as the browser, operating system, IP address, country and other geolocation data, date and time of visit, whether you are using a mobile device, referring websites, the search engine queries you used to get to the Web Site, the pages of the Web Site you visit and your activities on the Web Site such as what images, videos, or other embedded media you view, as well as the amount of time spent on the Web Site pages, and the number of pages visited. Some of this information may be collected using cookies, as further explained below. This information is used for a variety of purposes to improve the Web Site and its content, including without limitation to gather broad demographic data, identify trends and statistics, help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer the Web Site and its content. Digi-Key may also collect and share information between pages of the Web Site for the proper functioning of the Web Site, as well as authentication. Digi-Key may also use this information to provide you with information and advertising regarding our products and services.

**Cookies** – The Web Site may use "cookies" to provide information on your computer. Cookies are pieces of data that a website can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your computer or device. Digi-Key may use both session and persistent cookies on our own or through our third-party service providers as described below. Cookies may save your preferences while you are at the Web Site, such as allowing for persistent login on pages that require logging in, and Digi-Key may use them to provide you with tailored information and tracking as you use the Web Site services. Cookies help Digi-Key, among other things, to determine which areas of the Web Site are popular by tracking hits to those areas, which may in turn allow Digi-Key or our third-party providers to provide you with targeted information or advertising regarding Digi-Key’s products and services. By modifying your browser preferences, you may have the choice to accept cookies, to be notified when a cookie is sent, or to reject cookies. The rejection or limitation of cookies by your browser may limit your ability to use the Web Site.

Cookies we use fall into the categories below and usually have specific purposes of use:

**Cookie Category** | **Purpose of Cookies**  
---|---  
**Strictly Necessary** | These are general purpose platform session cookies, used to maintain an anonymous user session by the server.  
**Performance Based** | These cookies are used for web analytics to identify repeat visits by unique users, sometimes by assigning a randomly generated number as a client identifier. These cookies can also identify session and campaign data for analytics reports. By default, these cookies are set to expire after 2 years, although this is customizable by website owners.  
**Functionality** | These cookies are used to stored the visitor's geolocation, to record location and update a page share count, and track how often a user interacts with a web widget. These cookies can also identify unique identifiers for each page and test whether or not a browser is set to accept first party cookies.  
**Targeting** | These cookies are used for advertising, audience targeting, and provide a data management platform which enables cookies to capture real time profiling of visitor interests.  
**Unknown** | These cookies help manage availability and performance of software applications and the impact on user experience in the form of deep transaction tracing, synthetic monitoring, real user monitoring, and network monitoring. These cookies are also associated with managing sessions on load balanced servers, to ensure user requests are routed consistently to the correct server, usually the one that it is hosted on, but not always. These unknown cookies do not always have names or descriptions. They can change for each page on the site and different users will have different cookies. Different countries have different tags as well.  
  
**Third-Party Service Providers** – Digi-Key may use a variety of third-party services to help provide our services, to help us understand the use of our services, provide information and provide advertising regarding the Web Site and our products and services. Third-party services providers may include, but are not limited to third party web analytics services and a variety of third party social media platforms such as YouTube, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, and Google+. These third-party service providers may collect, store, and share information as further dictated by the privacy policies of those third parties.

_Google Analytics and Facebook –_

Digi-Key may use services through companies such as Google and Facebook to target ads to you related to your usage of the Web Site, such as to display advertising for the Web Site, products, and services on other websites you visit based on your activities on the Web Site in the past. Google may use the data collected to track and examine the use of the Web Site, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may also use the data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

Google Analytics uses "cookies" - text files that are saved on your computer and that enable the analysis of your use of the Web Site. The information generated by the cookie about your usage of this Web Site is generally transmitted to a Google server in the United States and saved there. Due to the activation of IP anonymization on these Web pages, however, your IP address will be truncated by Google beforehand within the member states of the European Union and other signatory states of the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be passed to a Google server in the United States and truncated there. On behalf of the operator of this Website, Google will use this information to evaluate your usage of the Website, to compile reports about Website activities, and to render further services for the Website operator in relation to Website and Internet usage. The IP address transmitted by your browser for the purposes of Google Analytics will not be associated with other Google data.

Digi-Key utilizes the User-ID feature of Google Analytics, which allows us to track individual users across multiple devices and sessions using the Web Site. You may view Google’s privacy policy here: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>,with more information located here: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/> (including information regarding how to control how information is shared through your Ads Settings) and here: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en>. 

The Web Site may use Google conversion tracking. If you reach our Web Site via an ad controlled by Google, Google AdWords places a cookie on your computer. The cookie is used for conversion tracking if a user clicks on an ad controlled by Google. If the user visits certain pages on our Web Site and the cookie has not yet expired, we and Google are able to detect that the user in question clicked the ad and was forwarded to the relevant page. The information collected using the conversion cookie enables the creation of conversion statistics for AdWords customers who have chosen to use conversion tracking. The customers are told the total number of users who clicked their ad and were forwarded to a page with a conversion tracking tag. However, they do not receive any information using this system that can be used to personally identify users.

If you do not wish to take part in tracking, you can decline the setting of the relevant cookie by means of a browser setting that generally deactivates the automatic setting of cookies. Please note that you must not delete the corresponding opt-out cookies if you wish to continue preventing measurement data from being recorded. If you delete all of the cookies in your browser, you must set any required opt-out cookies again.

You can prevent the collection of the data generated by Google Analytics in relation to your use of the Web site (including your IP address) and the processing of this data by downloading and installing the browser plug-in, with more information regarding how you can opt out of Google Analytics data collection as instructed here: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. This link provides instructions for installing an opt-out cookie on your device. As a result, the collection of data by Google Analytics is prevented in future for this Web Site and for this browser as long as the opt-out cookie remains installed in your browser.

Facebook similarly provides more information regarding the information it collects and how it is used in relation to advertising along with methods to opt out of collecting and sharing of information here: <https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads>; and <https://www.facebook.com/policy.php>.

Additional general information regarding opt-out from interest-based advertising from companies belonging to the Network Advertising Initiative can be found here: <http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#!/>, information regarding opting out through the Digital Advertising Alliance can be found here: <http://optout.aboutads.info/#!/>, and information regarding opting out through the European Digital Advertising Alliance (“EDAA”) may also be found here: <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/> and here: <https://www.edaa.eu/>.

**Web Beacons** \- We may employ Web beacons (also called single-pixel gifs), which are customized links or similar technologies, on the Web Site and when sending you messages, newsletters, or promotional emails or in using third-party service providers. Web beacons allow us to (a) determine whether you have opened, or acted upon, a promotional email and which links you have clicked on to deliver to you more focused communications and other content, (b) allow us to count the number of users who have visited certain webpages and effectively deliver services, and (c) enable us to compile aggregated statistics and determine the efficacy of promotions by using Web beacons from third parties.

**Online Chat** – Your online chat login information and communications conducted via the chat feature are recorded and stored by LivePerson, a third-party Application Service Provider. Digi-Key has access to LivePerson's recorded and stored chat information and may monitor or review such information for quality assurance. Digi-Key may also use that information in accordance with Digi-Key's Privacy Statement and Web Site Terms & Conditions. The use of the information by LivePerson is subject to the LivePerson Privacy Policy that can be found at the LivePerson web site: <https://www.liveperson.com/policies/privacy>.

### 3\. Sharing Of Your Information

Digi-Key may share information we collect through the Web Site, including personal information, with its product suppliers, for example, for market research and payment of commission to the supplier's agents.

Occasionally, Digi-Key may make the names and addresses of our customer list available to screened companies that offer products and/or services that may be of interest to you. You may elect to opt out of this use of your postal address by completing the "[Opt Out Form](https://www.digikey.in/classic/forms/dkc/www/servicesoptout.aspx?FormSite=IN&FormLang=en&site=IN&lang=en)."

Digi-Key may engage third party service providers, consultants, and independent contractors to perform functions and provide services for us including without limitation database management, advertising, and email service providers. Digi-Key may share the information we collect through the Web Site with these service providers so that they can perform services for us in relation to the Web Site and Digi-Key’s business.

If you have an open account with Digi-Key, credit and payment history will periodically be shared with credit reporting agencies.

In addition, Digi-Key may use and disclose customer information in special instances when Digi-Key has reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to investigate, identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interfering with Digi-Key’s rights or property, or the rights or property of others. We may disclose visitor information when subpoenaed, if ordered or otherwise required by a court of law, arbitrator, or other similar proceeding or the rules governing such a proceeding, for government investigations, with government agencies if required by law, and when Digi-Key otherwise believes in good faith that any applicable law requires it.

**Business Transfers** \- In the event that we are involved in a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, reorganization or sale of assets or change in our ownership or control, your information may be sold or transferred as part of that transaction.

### 4\. Your Right to Receive, Correct, Block, Delete, and Object to Stored Data.

You have the right to receive information about the personal data we hold about you at any time. You also have the right to the correction, blocking, or, except for the prescribed storage of data for business purposes or as otherwise legally required, deletion of your personal data. Please contact our data protection officer if you wish to request this. The contact details are provided at the end of this document.

So that data blocking can be observed at all times, this data must be kept in a block file for control purposes. You can also demand the deletion of data as long as the data in question is not subject to any legal archiving obligation. If an obligation of this kind does exist, we are happy to block your data if you request that we do so.

You can make changes to or revoke your consent to the storage of your data for the future at any time by notifying us accordingly.

### 5\. Other Information Practices 

**Security** – Digi-Key takes commercially reasonable steps to protect data, particularly financial information, transmitted through the Web Site. Digi-Key, however, cannot be responsible for and does not warrant the security of any information you transmit over the Internet, including using the Web Site. Digi-Key's site is equipped with Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology. Browsers that support the SSL encryption technology are called secure browsers. **Online orders to Digi-Key must be placed from a secure browser**. Your browser will automatically enter the secure mode when you make purchases. If you **do not** have a secure browser or would like to place orders using a method other than the Web Site, please review the Ordering FAQs for alternative ordering methods.

**Access to Personal Information for Reviewing, Editing, and/or Removing** \- If you wish to discuss this Privacy Statement and the information we collect, you may contact us at the address provided in this Privacy Statement.

**Children** \- The Web Site is not intended to solicit, collect or maintain personally identifiable information from users under the age of 13. If you are a parent or guardian, please contact us if you believe information regarding a child has been collected by us through our Web Site.

**Do Not Track** \- Presently the Web Site does not honor "do not track" settings on web browsers and does not offer you the opportunity to request that we not track your use of its services.

**Changes to this Policy** \- We may revise this Privacy Statement from time to time. The most current version of the Privacy Statement will govern our use of your information and will always be available. Please check this Privacy Statement often for changes. By continuing to access or use the Web Site after those changes become effective, you agree to be bound by the revised Privacy Statement and acknowledge that the revised Policy Statement applies to all information held by Digi-Key.

**Contacting Us** – 

**If you are outside of the E.U. and have questions about our use of information,** please contact us at [privacy@digikey.com](mailto:privacy@digikey.com). **For any other questions,** please contact us using the Communications Center (forms-based method of communicating with Digi-Key), or by contacting us at:

  * **_Outside the E.U._**
  * Digi-Key Electronics
  * 701 Brooks Avenue South
  * P.O. BOX 677
  * Thief River Falls, MN 56701-0677
  * Toll Free: 1-800-344-4539
  * Phone: 218-681-6674
  * Fax: 218-681-3380
  * Email: [sales@digikey.com](mailto:sales@digikey.com)

  * **_Inside the E.U._**
  * Digi-Key Electronics
  * Phone: +31 53 484 9584
  * Email: [eu.support@digikey.com](mailto:eu.support@digikey.com)

**If you are inside the E.U., with exception to Germany, and have questions about our use of your information, please contact our E.U. Representative, Hermann Reiter,** Managing Director of Digi-Key Electronics Germany Gmbh (located at Theresienhöhe 11a, 80339 Munich) using email: [privacy@digikey.com](mailto:privacy@digikey.com).

**If you are established in Germany and have questions about our use of your information, please contact our Data Protection Officer at email:** [privacy@digikey.com](mailto:privacy@digikey.com) **. Dr. Evelyne Sørensen** , Data protection and data security consultant activeMind AG Technologie- und Managementberatung

Calls to Digi-Key may be monitored and recorded for quality assurance purposes.

© 2019 Digi-Key Electronics, All Rights Reserved

## DATE OF LAST MODIFICATION

## May 25, 2018

Revision 2.0
